Guide to the William O. Douglas Collection 1920-1980
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
- Papers created and collected by Douglas, Series 1; 21 boxes
  - General Correspondence, 1922-1977; Sub-Series 5
    - Misc. correspondence /Lib. Of Congress Book Return/Bookbinding Order Form, 1941 (Box-folder 10/11)
    - Misc. correspondence / War Production Board Preference Rating Certificate, 1942 (Box-folder 10/12)
    - Misc. correspondence, January-April 1943 (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Misc. correspondence / Net Cash Sheet, May-December 1943 (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Misc. correspondence / Valentine from 'Bumble'/ Letter From R. Forman Captain, 1944 (Box-folder 10/15)
    - Misc. correspondence / NY Visit Itinerary/US Senate Copy of Senator Maloney Letter/ Bookbinder Invoice/ Letter From Soldier/ Letter From Chicago Cardinals Football From 'Jim', January-June 1945 (Box-folder 10/16)
    - Misc. correspondence / Copies of Misc. correspondence, July-December 1945 (Box-folder 10/17)
    - General correspondence / From Winslow Anderson to Overseers of WC, January-June 1946 (Box-folder 10/18)
    - General correspondence, July-December 1946 (Box-folder 10/19)
    - General correspondence, January-June 1947 (Box-folder 10/20)
    - General correspondence / From Winslow Anderson WC, July-December 1947 (Box-folder 10/21)
    - General correspondence / Constitution WA State and Alaska Society of the Dist. Of Columbia, January-July 1948 (Box-folder 10/22)
    - Letters RE. Run For Presidencey/ Yale Law Journal Banquet Speech/'The Great Rehearsal' Van Dorsen, 1948 (Box-folder 10/23)
    - General correspondence, September-December 1948 (Box-folder 10/24)
    - Misc. correspondence / Ninth Circuit Judges, District Judges List, January-May 1949 (Box-folder 10/25)
    - Misc. correspondence / 'Plants Collected by W.O.D. In Lebanon in 1949'/ Photocopy of Letter, June-December 1949 (Box-folder 10/26)
    - Misc. correspondence, January-May 1950 (Box-folder 10/27)
    - Misc. correspondence / 'List of Himalayan Wild Flower Seeds Collected for W.O.D.' (2 Copies), June-December 1950 (Box-folder 10/28)
    - Misc. correspondence / Letter From Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction, January-March 1951 (Box-folder 10/29)
    - Misc. correspondence / Letters Re. W.O.D. Article in Look Magazine, April 1951 (Box-folder 10/30)
    - Misc. correspondence, May-July 1951 (Box-folder 10/31)
    - Misc. correspondence / Pamphlet on James Forrestal Research Center, August-October 1951 (Box-folder 10/32)
    - General correspondence, November-December 1951 (Box-folder 10/33)
    - General correspondence, January-February 1952 (Box-folder 10/34)
    - General correspondence Re. Presidencial Candidacy, March 1952 (Box-folder 10/35)
    - General correspondence / Testimony of Robert M. Hutchins, April-May 1952 (Box-folder 10/36)
    - General correspondence/ Books Returned to the Library by EA, June-August 1952 (Box-folder 10/37)
    - General correspondence, September-October 1952 (Box-folder 10/38)
    - General correspondence, November-December 1952 (Box-folder 10/39)
    - General correspondence/ Adlai Stevenson Recommendation/Telegram Copies/ Lunch Invite, January-March 1953 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - General correspondence, April-October 1953 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - General correspondence / "Mexican Contract Naturals" Chart/ Judicial Robe Order Form, November-December 1953 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Misc. correspondence / "America's Bookless Santa Claus: An Editorial", by Stanley Young, January-April 1954 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - General correspondence, May-September 1954 (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Misc. correspondence / Look Magazine--Russian Trip Expenses (2 Copies)/ Memoir?, October-December 1954 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Misc. correspondence / "Schedule for Visit to Boston", January-April 1955 (Box-folder 11/7)
    - General correspondence, May-September 1955 (Box-folder 11/8)
    - General Correspondence, October-December 1955 (Box-folder 11/9)
    - General Correspondence 1956 Jan-March, January-March 1956 (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Misc. Correspondence / "Acceptances for Dinner for Chief"/ "A Christmas Rarebit", April-July 1956 (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Misc. Correspondence, September-December 1956 (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Misc. Correspondence / "Memorandum of Agreement" between W.O.D. and Publisher, January-March 1957 (Box-folder 11/13)
    - Misc. Correspondence, April-July 1957 (Box-folder 11/14)
    - Misc. Correspondence / "Remarks of W.O.D. on the Presentation of His Collection Of Himalayan Wildflowers to the National Herbarium (3 Copies), August-December 1957 (Box-folder 11/15)
    - Misc. Correspondence / "Multi National Trade Union Specialists:, 1958 (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Correspondence / Article on Tibet by W.O.D./ Report of Advisory Board of Advanced Religious Studies To Board of Directors of Union Theological Seminary/Report of Ninth Circuit Judicial Conference Bankruptcy Committee/ "Our Historic Freedoms: Where Do They Stand Today?" by Walter L. Pope, 1959 (Box-folder 11/17)
    - Correspondence / Mining Accident Note/ "Report of the Board of Advisors to the Board of Directors of Union Theological Seminary/ "By-Laws of The Albert Parvin Foundation"/ "Articles of Incorporation of The Albert Parvin Foundation", 1960 (Box-folder 11/18)
    - Misc. Correspondence / "Law Libraries- Underdeveloped Nations" Book List/ "Reorganization of the Department of State" (3 Copies), 1961 (Box-folder 11/19)
    - Correspondence / Overseas Education Fund of the League of Women Voters/ Special Events Division Seattle World's Fair- India Week/ "University of the Americas" John Wiley/ Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs Biographical Data/ Requests for Parvin Lecturers/ Conservation Projects for the Ford Foundation/ Memorandum to the Ford Foundation, 1962 (Box-folder 11/20)
    - Correspondence Jan.-Oct./ NYC Itinerary/ Memorandum to the Board of Directors The Parvin Foundation, 1963 (Box-folder 11/21)
    - Misc. Correspondence / Misc. Itineraries/ Misc. Receipts/ Memorandum Re. Wilderness Movies, 1964 (Box-folder 11/22)
    - Correspondence / Drawing of W.O.D./Center of the Study of Democratic Institutions Memorandum/Meeting of The Albert Parvin Foundation Minutes/ Excerpt from Letter from Geneva, 1965 (Box-folder 11/23)
    - General Correspondence / Letter RE. William O. Douglas Award, 1966 (Box-folder 11/24)
    - Misc. Correspondence / International Banquet in Honor of Ernest Gruening/ Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions:Pacem In Terris II, Geneva Switzerland; Speakers and Panelists (2 Copies)/ Ibid; Participants (2 Copies) / Ibid; Acceptances Panel, 1967 (Box-folder 11/25)
    - General Correspondence / Assessor's Notices, Yakima County/ Materials Re. Young People of America, 1968 (Box-folder 11/26)
    - General Correspondence/ Materials Re. Mexican Conference, 1969 (Box-folder 11/27)
    - General Correspondence / Misc. Receipts/ "Memorandum on the Role of Counsel and Related Procedural Matters/ Plans for reorganization of the Center for the Study of Democratic Intsitutions/, 1970 (Box-folder 11/28)
    - General Correspondence, 1971 (Box-folder 11/29)
    - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 11/30)
    - General Correspondence/ Misc. Receipts, 1973 (Box-folder 11/31)
    - General Correspondence / Misc. Receipts/ Enrollment Report; Consortium of Metropolitan Law Schools, 1974 (Box-folder 11/32)
    - General Correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 11/33)
    - General Correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 11/34)
    - General Correspondence/ Pamphlet Re. Big Bend National Park Texas, 1977 (Box-folder 11/35)
    - General Correspondence, Undated (Box-folder 11/36)
  - Manuscripts, 1938-1970; Sub-Series 6
    - Writings on the Environment, 1970 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - We Become Internationalists (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Writings on Africa (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Writings on Hunting and Fishing (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Manuscript on the "Free Exercise" and "Establishment of Religion" (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Writings on India, Pakistan, Kashmir (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Writings on Puerto Rico (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Writings on Australia (Box-folder 16/8)
    - Writings on Vietnam, Cambodia (Box-folder 16/9)
    - Writings on Thailand (Box-folder 16/10)
    - Writings on The Phillipines (Box-folder 16/11)
    - Writings on Germany (Box-folder 16/12)
    - Writings on the United States (Box-folder 16/13)
    - Writings on China, Tibet (Box-folder 16/14)
    - Writings on Canada (Box-folder 16/15)
    - Writings on Russia (Box-folder 16/16)
    - Writings on Middle East (Box-folder 16/17)
    - Writings on Greece (Box-folder 16/18)
    - Writings on Japan, Taiwan, Singapore, Korea, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Malaysia (Box-folder 16/19)
    - Various Quotes, not written by W.O.D. (Box-folder 16/20)
    - Writings on the Yakima (now Yakama) Tribe (Box-folder 16/21)
    - Writings on The Cascades/Indian Legends Concerning Cascades (Box-folder 16/22)
    - Manuscript - "The North Cascades" (National Geographic Expedition, 1965 (Box-folder 16/23)
    - Fragments of Draft of Go East, Young Man (Box-folder 16/24)
    - Writings on Legal System (US) Misc. (Box-folder 16/25)
    - Writings, The Living Bill of Rights (Box-folder 16/26)
    - Writings, Misc. (Box-folder 16/27)
    - Manuscripts (2) of Book, "Russian Journey" and Fragments, 12/21/1955 (Box-folder 16/28)
    - Manuscript "One Hour of Justice": -Tribes of Persia, -Walking Tour of Lebanon, -Summary, Undated (Box-folder 16/29)
    - Manuscripts 3 4, Three Worlds, 1952 (Box-folder 16/30)
    - Writings, Indo-China, 1953 (Box-folder 16/31)
    - Manuscript and Fragments, "The On-Going Revolution: China's Problem- and Ours" (Box-folder 16/32)
    - Manuscript on "The On-Going Revolution" 1 of 2 (Box-folder 16/33)
    - Writings, "The Basic Issues of the Next Ten Years", 11/10/1962 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Writings, Outline of Four Periods in US History", Undated (Box-folder 17/2)
    - Writings, Outline of US Supreme Court in History, Undated (Box-folder 17/3)
    - Biography on W.O.D. by The Research Division of Americans for Democratic Action, Undated (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Writings, Article: Sovereignty of the Individual, Playboy, 1968 (Box-folder 17/5)
    - Writings, Press Release/ Appeal San Gorgonio Wilderness, Undated (Box-folder 17/6)
    - Writings, Press Release, Russia Today, Knox College, 5/15/1962 (Box-folder 17/7)
    - Misc., Undated (Box-folder 17/8)
    - Research, Notes from the Journals of Lewis Clark, Undated (Box-folder 17/9)
    - Technological Advances, Undated (Box-folder 17/10)
    - Editorials, Undated (Box-folder 17/11)
    - Wilderness, 1941-1965 (Box-folder 17/12)
    - WWII, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 17/13)
    - SEC, 1938 (Box-folder 17/14)
    - Articles from Eliot Janeway, 1943-1960 (Box-folder 17/15)
    - W.O.D. in the News, Yakima, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 17/16)
    - W.O.D. in the News, Marriage to Mrs. Mercedes Davidson, 1954 (Box-folder 17/17)
    - W.O.D. in the News, Book Reviews, 1950 (Box-folder 17/18)
    - Instincts, Culture and Science, 1958 (Box-folder 17/19)
    - Writings, An Inquest on our Lakes and Rivers, Undated (Box-folder 17/20)
    - Writings, The Public Trial and the Free Press in Nieman Reports, July 1960 (Box-folder 17/21)
    - Writings, The Right of Association, 1963 (Box-folder 17/22)
    - Writings, Law Reviews and Full Disclosure, 1965 (Box-folder 17/23)
    - Faith in Bill of Rights Must Be Reviewed, says Justice Douglas. Seattle Times, 12/14/1958 (Box-folder 17/24)
    - Press Releases, 1956 (Box-folder 17/25)
    - Vagrancy and Arrest on Suspicion (Excerpts from Lecture at U of NM) in the Minority of One, May 1960 (Box-folder 17/26)
    - Peace within Our Grasp (From Abridged Speech) in the Nation, 4/30/1949 (Box-folder 17/27)
    - Biography by Marian D. Irish, U of Florida Law Review, Winter 1953 (Box-folder 17/28)
    - Speeches, Announcement for Speech on Managing the Docket of the Supreme Court of the US, 3/19/1950 (Box-folder 17/29)
    - Trident Press Release RE 6th Vol. in Credo Series, The Anatomy of Liberty, 1963 (Box-folder 17/30)
    - Writings, The C and O Canal, 1959 (Box-folder 17/31)
    - Writings, It is Not Too Late to Save Our Wilderness, 9/26/1965 (Box-folder 17/32)
    - Itineraries and Schedule of Appointments SEC, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 17/33)
    - Writings, The Aversion to the Military, Undated (Box-folder 17/34)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. I, Undated (Box-folder 21/1)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. II, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. II Folder 2, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 21/3)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. III Folder 1, 1956-1968 (Box-folder 21/4)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. III Folder 2, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 21/5)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. IV, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 21/6)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. V Folder 1, Undated (Box-folder 21/7)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. V Folder 2, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 21/8)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. VI, 1956-1961 (Box-folder 21/9)
    - American Legal System: Part 1 Ch. IX, 1959 (Box-folder 21/10)
    - American Legal System: Part 2 Ch. I, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 17/35)
    - American Legal System: Part 3 Ch. I, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 17/36)
    - American Legal System: Part 3 Ch. II, 1951-1961 (Box-folder 17/37)
    - American Legal System: Part 3 Ch. III, 1961 (Box-folder 17/38)
    - American Legal System: Part 3 Ch. IV, 1958 (Box-folder 17/39)
    - American Legal System: Part 3 Ch. V, 1960 (Box-folder 17/40)
    - American Legal System: Part 3 Ch. VII, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 17/41)
    - American Legal System: The Decalogue Journal, 1955 (Box-folder 17/42)
    - American Legal System: Part 2 Ch. XV, No. 1, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 17/43)
    - American Legal System: Part 2 Ch. XV, No. 2, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 17/44)
    - American Legal System: Part 2 Ch. XVI, 1959 (Box-folder 17/45)
    - The Three Hundred Year War, Undated (Box-folder 17/46)
    - American Legal System: Part 2 Ch. II, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 17/47)
    - American Legal System: Part 2 Ch. VII, 1958 (Box-folder 17/48)
    - American Legal System: Part 2 Ch. VI, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 17/49)
    - American Legal System: Part 2 Ch. XI, 1960 (Box-folder 17/50)
    - American Legal System: Part 2 Ch. XII, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 17/51)
    - Reports and Law Reviews, 1954 (Box-folder 17/52)
    - Religion, 1955-1965 (Box-folder 17/53)
  - Speeches, 1936-1973; Sub-Series 7
    - ABA Address, 7/29/1936 (Box-folder 18/19)
    - Memorandum RE. Speech Before ABA on Municipal Protective Committees, July 1936 (Box-folder 18/20)
    - Moody Lecture, Various Drafts, 10/ 20-21,26/1936 (Box-folder 18/21)
    - Bond Club Speech, 3/23/1937 (Box-folder 18/22)
    - Dept. of Agriculture Address, 4/14/1937 (Box-folder 18/23)
    - Scatteration V. Integration of Public Utility Systems, 1938 (Box-folder 18/24)
    - SEC and Insurance Companies, Connecticut (Hartford), circa 1938 (Box-folder 18/25)
    - Address of W.O.D. to the Association of Stock Exchange Firms, NY,NY, 5/20/1938 (Box-folder 18/26)
    - The Role of the SEC. Speech Given at Yale, 4/27/1938 (Box-folder 18/27)
    - SEC Pacific Stock Exchange, 6/11/1938 (Box-folder 18/28)
    - SEC and Conservative Business Management, 9/20/1938 (Box-folder 18/29)
    - Peace in Time of War. (and draft), 9/28/1938 (Box-folder 18/30)
    - SEC Partial Speech, 9/27/1938 (Box-folder 18/31)
    - On Legislation, Laissez-faire and Control SEC, NY, 10/21/1938 (Box-folder 18/32)
    - Partial from NY H-T Forum, 10/23/1938 (Box-folder 18/33)
    - Cooperation Between Business and Government, Harvard Club, 11/7/1938 (Box-folder 18/34)
    - SEC: Explanation of Boston Talks, 11/8/1938 (Box-folder 18/35)
    - SEC, 11/23/1938 (Box-folder 18/36)
    - Democracy in Industry and Finance (SEC?), circa 1938 (Box-folder 18/11)
    - National Emergency Council's Report on the South, circa 1938-1939 (Box-folder 18/10)
    - Remarks at Southern Policy Committee Dinner, 3/2/1939 (Box-folder 18/37)
    - Speech to Baker, Oregon Chamber of Commerce, 9/1/1942 (Box-folder 18/37.5)
    - The Remsen Bird Lectures. The College and Society Occidental College, 1949 (Box-folder 18/38)
    - Address at National Book Award, 1/27/1953 (Box-folder 18/39)
    - Democratic Fronts Against Communism: The Middle East and South Asia, Ohio State U, 5/12/1953 (Box-folder 18/30)
    - The Trial of Sir Walter Raleigh and the US Court System: American Law University, 5/20/1953 (Box-folder 18/31)
    - Marcus Whitman Statue Dedication, Rotunda of the US Capitol, 5/22/1953 (Box-folder 18/32)
    - Democracy and the Dignity of Man: Symposium at American University, D.C., 5/27/1955 (Box-folder 18/33)
    - America and Russia: 1956, 3/5/1956 (Box-folder 18/34)
    - Asia's Medical Problems, Jacobi Medical Society, D.C., 3/24/1956 (Box-folder 18/35)
    - Misunderstandings Between East and West, 4/17/1956 (Box-folder 18/36)
    - The Bill of Rights, Franklin and Marshall College, Lancaster, PA, 5/7-8/1956 (Box-folder 18/37)
    - Commencement Address at Haverford College, 5/27/1958 (Box-folder 18/38)
    - The Moslem Revolution, Rotary Club, Portland OR., 8/12/1958 (Box-folder 18/39)
    - Books Break Barriers, Middle Atlantic Regional Library Conference: Atlantic City, NJ, 10/2/1958 (Box-folder 18/40)
    - The Role of the Lawyer, Dalhousie University: Halifax, Nova Scotia, 11/1/1958 (Box-folder 18/41)
    - The Means and the End, January 1959 (Box-folder 18/42)
    - Introduction for Mrs. F.D. Roosevelt, 1959 (Box-folder 18/43)
    - Judges, Juries and Bureaucrats, U of New Hampshire, 10/28/1959 (Box-folder 18/44)
    - Vagrancy and Arrest on Suspicion, John Fiels Simms Memorial Lecture, 3/15/1960 (Box-folder 18/45)
    - Vagrancy and Arrest on Suspicion, U of New Mexico Law School, 3/15/1960 (Box-folder 18/46)
    - Democracy vs. Communism in Asia, LA City College, 4/16/1959 (Box-folder 18/47)
    - The Public Trial and the Free Press, U of Colorado, 5/10/1960 (Box-folder 18/48)
    - Arizona's New Judicial Article, Pima County Bar Assoc., 10/25/1960 (Box-folder 18/49)
    - Revolutions, Rotary Club of WA, 8/24/1961 (Box-folder 18/50)
    - The Rule of Law in World Affairs; Athens, Greece, 10/23/1961 (Box-folder 18/51)
    - Exporting the Law; Kansas City Bar Association, 5/1/1962 (Box-folder 18/52)
    - Consular Courts; Kansas City Bar Assoc., 5/1/1962 (Box-folder 18/53)
    - The Importance of History and the Natural Environment; Minnesota Historical Society, St. Paul, MN, 5/26/1962 (Box-folder 18/54)
    - Losing Ground in the Undeveloped Countries; Yeshiva University, Detroit, Michigan, 6/6/1962 (Box-folder 18/55)
    - The Decline of Western Prestige; U of Judaism, Los Angeles, CA, 7/1/1962 (Box-folder 18/56)
    - Civil Rights, Civil Liberties Educational Foundation; Warrenton, VA, 11/17/1962 (Box-folder 18/57)
    - Democracy and Revolution Fund for the Republic; Santa Barbara, CA, 12/1/1962 (Box-folder 18/58)
    - Israel, 15th Annual Hanukah Dinner for Progressive Israel, 12/9/1962 (Box-folder 18/59)
    - Dinner in Honor of Carl Sandburg; Waldorf Astoria Hotel, NYC,NY, 1/6/1963 (Box-folder 18/60)
    - Remarks if William O. Douglas Introducing Adlai Stevenson, 1/22/1963 (Box-folder 18/61)
    - Copy of Speech Given by James T. Brady in Santa Barbara, CA, 2/12/1963 (Box-folder 18/62)
    - Bill of Rights, National Civil Liberties Clearing House; Wash. D.C., 3/28/1963 (Box-folder 18/63)
    - Our Disappearing Wilderness, National Resources Council; Waterville, Maine, 6/14/1963 (Box-folder 18/64)
    - Education on the Bill of Rights; New Jersey Education Association; Trenton, NJ, 10/5/1963 (Box-folder 18/65)
    - Bill of Rights, Cedar Lane Unitarian Church; Bethesda, MD, 10/6/1963 (Box-folder 18/66)
    - Church and State- At Home and Abroad; Phi Beta Kappa Associates, 11/12/1963 (Box-folder 18/67)
    - Rule of Law, Bnai Zion; NYC, 12/15/1963 (Box-folder 18/68)
    - Church and State- At Home and Abroad; Jewish Theological Seminary Detroit, MI, 1/20/1964 (Box-folder 18/69)
    - New Potential Sources of Energy; Harvard Business School Club of PA; Philadelphia, PA, 3/18/1964 (Box-folder 18/70)
    - Mongolians and Conservation; The Alachua Audubon Society; Gainesville, Florida, 4/7/1964 (Box-folder 18/71)
    - Mongolians and Conservation; The Conservation Foundation, 4/30/1964 (Box-folder 18/72)
    - Equality and Apartheid; U of Minnesota; Minneapolis, Minnesota, 5/7/1964 (Box-folder 18/73)
    - The Establishment and Society; The Guidance Center; New Rochelle, NY, 5/23/1964 (Box-folder 18/74)
    - Colonialism and America; Parsons College, 6/6/1964 (Box-folder 18/75)
    - Address by William O. Douglas at a Testimonial Dinner for Seniel Ostrow; Los Angeles, CA, 7/25/1964 (Box-folder 18/76)
    - The Church and Pluralistic Society; Unitarian Chirch of Rockville, 11/15/1964 (Box-folder 18/77)
    - Some Aspects of Universal Distrust; Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 12/16/1964 (Box-folder 18/78)
    - Pax America; Address to American Foreigh Law Assoc.; NY,NY, 2/1/1965 (Box-folder 18/79)
    - American Foreign Law Assoc.; NY, NY, 2/1/1965 (Box-folder 18/80)
    - The Rule of Law in World Affairs; American Foreign Law Assoc.; NY,Ny, 2/1/1965 (Box-folder 18/81)
    - Address to the Judicial Conference of the Americas; San Juan, Puerto Rico, 5/26/1965 (Box-folder 18/82)
    - Universal Distrust; Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions; Santa Barbara, CA., 12/26/1965 (Box-folder 18/83)
    - Increase and Need for Legal Services/ Civil Rights, circa 1966 (Box-folder 18/8)
    - 40th Anniversary- Class of 1926- Columbia Law, Columbia University Club; NY, NY, 4/2/1966 (Box-folder 18/84)
    - Law in Israel; American Friends of the Hebrew University, 4/17/1967 (Box-folder 18/85)
    - Economic Man in the US; Ansonia Independent Democrats; NYC, 4/23/1967 (Box-folder 18/86)
    - Conservation, the Constitution, the Bill of Rights, and Problems in the World, 4/26/1967 (Box-folder 18/87)
    - Freedom of Speech and Civil Rights; Marguette University; Milwaukee, WI, 5/1/1967 (Box-folder 18/88)
    - America Revisits Asia; City College; New York, NY, 5/9/1967 (Box-folder 18/89)
    - Pacem- in- Terris; Geneva, Switzerland, 5/28/1967 (Box-folder 18/90)
    - Israeli Law; hebrew University, Jerusalem, 6/23/1967 (Box-folder 18/91)
    - Question of Missiles and Defense Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions; NY, NY, 11/19/1967 (Box-folder 18/92)
    - Announcements of Lectureship Series: NYU, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Federal Courts and the Democratic System; Alabama Chapter ACLU; Tuscaloosa, Alabama, 4/20/1968 (Box-folder 18/93)
    - American Attitudes Toward Asia; Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions; Santa Barbara, CA, 1/24-25/1969 (Box-folder 18/94)
    - Education, Israel and the World Order; N.E. Hebrew Academy, 3/23/1969 (Box-folder 18/95)
    - Keeping Government Off the Backs of People; Oregon State University; Corvallis, OR, 4/9/1969 (Box-folder 18/96)
    - Address Given at the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions Conference; Mexico City, Mexico, 9/9/1969 (Box-folder 18/97)
    - Memorial of Mr. Justice Holmes; Washington D.C., 11/20/1969 (Box-folder 18/98)
    - Headstart Program, circa 1970 (Box-folder 18/99)
    - Charles Hughes, Stone, Vinson; Remarks to Multnomah County bar Assoc.; Portland, OR., 9/25/1971 (Box-folder 18/100)
    - Simon E. Sobeloff Memorial, circa 1973 (Box-folder 18/101)
    - Summary of Remarks at Colgate on, 6/3/1973 (Box-folder 18/102)
    - Introduction of W.O.D. by Carl Sandburg, Undated (Box-folder 18/1)
    - Boston Press Conference, Undated (Box-folder 18/3)
    - Speech Given at New Haven, New England, Undated (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Man's Inhumanity To Land, Undated (Box-folder 18/5)